♪ In the
not-too-distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday, A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
(rocket ship whirs)
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ Cambot! ♪
♪ Pan left! ♪
♪ Gypsy! ♪
♪ Hi, girl! ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ What a cool guy ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ He's a wisecracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself ♪
♪ It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(whirring)
- As the noose was fitted,
and as a delicate black mask
was tied around the
prisoner's eyes,
may the Lord have mercy on--
- Eh, boring!
- Boring.
(grumbles)
- Oh hi everybody, welcome
to the satellite of love,
I'm Joel Robinson and
I'm with my robots,
Tom Servo and Crow T. Robot.
And I'm reading them some
really scary bedtime stories.
But they're so jaded, I mean,
kids today have seen and
heard everything, believe me.
- [Robotic voice] Oh,
isn't that the truth?
Commercial sign in 30 seconds.
- C'mon, Joel, you've
been reading us
nothing but the light stuff!
"In Cold Blood,"
"Helter-Skelter,"
the 17 novels that Stephen
King published this year.
Come on!
Read us something really scary.
- Yeah, come on.
- Okay,
I've been saving a
really, really scary one.
That is, if you guys
think you're old enough,
if you think you can handle it.
- Oh, I'm sure
it's really scary.
Do I dare ask what it's called?
- "Life's Little
Instruction Book."
(screams)
- Oh no!
- Okay, number one.
Put a lot of little marshmallows
in your hot chocolate.
(both scream)
Number two.
Surprise a new neighbor
with one of your
favorite homemade dishes.
(gasp)
And include the recipe.
- Not the recipe!
- Number three.
At the movies, buy Junior Mints
and sprinkle them
on your popcorn!
(garbled yells)
Number four, enjoy
real maple syrup.
- The humor, the humor!
(upbeat synth music)
- Number 187.
Measure people by the
size of their hearts,
not by the size of
their bank accounts.
- Ugh, that's enough, Joel,
I can't take any
more, please, no!
- Keep going, keep going.
- What are you, crazy?
- Okay.
Number 188.
When facing a difficult task,
act as though it's
impossible to fail.
When going after Moby Dick,
take along the tartar sauce.
(both scream)
Hold the phone, you two, Mum
Mum and Pee Pop are calling.
- That's nothing, Joel.
Clive Barker says, "I have
seen the future of horror
"and it's 'Everything
I Need to Know,
"I Learned in Kindergarten.'"
(evil laugh)
- Ready with the invention
exchange, Chiefirino.
- Each day, Frank and I
are consumed with many
time constraints,
what with the mountain of
paperwork here at the lab,
Frank's social calendar,
and my jazzercise,
we just don't have
time to relax.
At the odd occasion we
do have an evening free
to take in, say, a film,
we run around here like ninnies,
trying to shower and
shave and get there
only to spend a
half hour in line.
- So do what I do.
Don't get ready to go
until you're already there!
How?
It's easy!
With the new Frank-brand
Quik-Primp kit.
- That's right.
Spend that down time in line
doing something productive
like teasing your brow, or
finding your natural part.
Now, say, for
demonstration purposes
Frank and I are in
line to see, oh,
"Out On a Limb."
- Well in that case,
we'd be seated already.
- Frank.
- Okay, just for
argument's sake,
let's say we're on line
to see "Out On a Limb."
Anyway.
Now I'm not nearly ready to go.
But it doesn't matter.
I merely take this
light and portable
Frank-brand full-length mirror.
Then I quickly secure
the whisper-weight
Frank-brand toiletry chapeau.
(groans)
Really kind of depends
on the good graces
of the person standing
in front of you.
I find average height
really works best.
(laughs)
I'll be done in just a...
Do I look fat to you?
Just a second.
Hey.
(laughs)
Back up to you, Mr. R.
- Well our invention
exchange this week
takes us to the world of art.
- Abstract expressionism,
it's what's hot!
All the kids are dying for it.
(laughs)
- That's why we did the
paint-by-number Mark Rothko.
Now even little Johnny can
join the color-filled painters
and challenge the
convention of the art world!
- Yeah, let's see here.
We got our Number Five paint,
it says number five here.
We just paint the brush
and start painting.
(both stammer)
- It's fun!
- Uh, Joel,
are you sure you're
doing that right?
Let's take a look
at the box, eh?
- Yeah, let's see what.
Oh, what do you know?
- Looks pretty good to me.
- Whaddaya think, sirs?
- I don't know much about
art, but I know what I like.
And I like today's film.
You young Turks are in
for the wackiest ride
since Richard Pryor
boarded the Silver Streak.
Please enjoy "The Rebel Set."
But first, an aptly-named film
entitled "Johnny at the Fair."
- More like that?
- No no no no,
right at the center.
- Like down?
- Down, the other way.
- That's fine.
- What do you want?
- Holy then movie starts!
(screams)
(doors whir, clank)
- [Joel] Come on you
guys, now this is a short.
I don't want us
getting too dark.
- [Crow] Okay, okay.
- [Joel] I know, it's a new
band from Seattle, right?
- [Crow] I'm gonna
get Joe Louis.
- [Servo] Oh, Barbara Ann Scott,
the white bomber, I suppose?
- [Crow] Olsen and
Johnson, keeps babies soft.
- [Joel] And Johnny, the
Wonder Something-or-other.
- [Servo] Look, it's
the Arc de Full Retreat.
- [Crow] Prozac, get
work in today's society.
- [Voiceover] This is
the story of Johnny.
- [Joel] A sad story.
- [Narrator] It all
happened the day Johnny
and his mother and
dad crossed the border
to see the famous Canadian
National Exhibition.
- [Servo] Oh, that sounds great.
- [Narrator] It was Johnny's
first real grown-up trip,
and there were
many things to see.
- [Crow] This is the last
you'll see Johnny happy.
- [Narrator] There
were exhibits on radio,
electricity,
flowers, photography,
a real land of wonders.
- [Robots] Boring.
- [Narrator] And a
whole Scottish band.
Johnny even got to
the midway for a ride,
but the fun didn't last
nearly long enough.
- [Servo] Johnny's
car rolled and burned.
- [Narrator] There were displays
from all over the world.
From countries Johnny
was just learning about.
Fine porcelains from France.
Riches from the Orient.
Silks and pearls from India.
- [Joel] Simulated
culture like Disney World.
- [Narrator] It had
been a busy morning,
but Johnny's adventure really
began before lunchtime.
- [Crow] A shot rang out!
- [Narrator] Everyone was
having a good time but it's
hard to decide where to go next.
- [Joel] How 'bout home?
- [Narrator] "Let's go back
to the midway," he says,
pointing in the wrong direction.
"What Johnny?
"No, Johnny" says mom, "we're
going to the art gallery."
- [Servo] And you'll like it!
- [Crow] (imitating petulant
child) No I don't wanna go!
- [Narrator] That's no fun.
Let's see what a fella
can find for himself.
- [Joel] Johnny's negligent
parents let him wander off.
- [Servo] (imitating child)
Haight Ashbury, please?
Ding ding ding.
- [Narrator] Johnny's
parents still can't decide.
At first, they don't miss him.
- [Crow] Who, what?
- [Narrator] Then.
- [Servo] A feeling of elation.
- [Narrator] Where's Johnny?
Where did that boy go?
With 250,000 people here,
how will we ever find him?
- [Servo] Johnny's parents
decide to move on and start
their lives anew.
- [Narrator] "Ah,"
thinks Johnny.
- [Crow] (imitating
child) Ah, sweet freedom.
- [Narrator] With 15 cents in
his pocket and an afternoon
ahead of him, Johnny puts
his best foot forward.
He isn't sure where he's
going, but he's on his way.
- [Servo] Girls!
- [Crow] Run, John, run!
- [Narrator] Then Johnny
hears a sound that
starts him running.
A baseball game.
Oh, boy!
When he gets there, he
finds a five year old can't
get close enough
to see anything.
- [Servo] Besides, the Mariners
are playing, so who cares?
- [Narrator] Unless someone
lifts you up and puts
you on the lap of the undefeated
champion of the world,
Joe Louis.
- [Crow] Joe hits Johnny
up for 15 cents due to
tax problems.
(groans)
- [Joel] Half the pain of
having feet is Red Goose shoes.
- [Narrator] Next
stop, the horse show.
Johnny loves horses.
He's just in time,
for the judges are about
to award the prize.
- [Servo] And it goes to Johnny!
(chuckles)
- [Narrator] The winner
is this white beauty.
- [Crow] (imitating
horse) Oh, my ear!
Ow!
Geez, the horse from Equus
had it better than this.
- [Servo] Then Johnny
transmogrifies, he's
a shape shifter.
And he breaks the fourth seal.
- [Narrator] It's a
five day old Shetland.
And was born right at the fair.
He weighs all of 24 pounds and
is just under two feet tall.
- [Joel] His parents didn't
abandon him like Johnny's.
(suckles)
- [Crow] Oops, sorry dad.
- [Servo] Johnny feels dark
hands pressing him onward.
The voices in his
head get meaner.
- [Narrator] Johnny
can't read the words
"Chemical Wonderland."
- [Joel] Oh, we've
all been there.
- [Narrator] He thinks
he'll check on things.
- [Crow] A whiskery man
hands him a small package,
"The first one's free," he says.
- [Narrator] In a little
vat, and low and behold
before his very eyes.
- [Servo] LSD.
- [Narrator] A rubber ball.
- [Servo] (disappointed) Oh.
- [Narrator] Thank you!
- [Joel] Johnny must have
everything for himself.
- [Narrator] Johnny's
off for more adventures.
Gee whiz, I'll be they don't
have anything like this
in the art gallery.
- [Crow] Johnny distracts
the tightrope walkers
and they fall to certain doom.
- [Narrator] And
on bicycles, too.
- [Joel] Boy, they're sure
tough on drunk drivers
in Canada.
- [Narrator] Johnny is invited
to help put on the show.
And don't think he
doesn't enjoy himself.
- [Joel] That's a guy!
- [Narrator] Afterwards,
Johnny can't stop going up
and down.
- [Crow] The drugs from
the chemical wonderland
start to kick in.
(chuckles)
- [Narrator] Johnny's mother
is still trying to find
her missing son,
and thinks she might see
Johnny on the edge of the crowd
gathered to hear the
former Prime Minister.
- [Joel] Yeah, right.
- [Narrator] Mr. Mackenzie King.
She never dreams that
Johnny is on the platform,
discussing the situation
with the guest speaker.
- [Servo] Tell me, Johnny,
what do you think of the new
free trade agreement?
- [Crow] I have to go horsies.
- [Joel] What was
his name again?
Jimmy, no Jerry?
- [Narrator] Johnny gets an
escort down from the platform
and is off again.
- [Crow] It will be the
first of many encounters
with bouncers for Johnny.
(Servo honks)
- [Narrator] Oh, boy,
a helicopter airplane.
- [Servo] What?
- [Narrator] "Jimminy,"
thinks Johnny.
"If only I could get a
ride in one of those."
- [Servo] Visions of the
Mekong Delta flash before
Johnny's eyes.
- [Narrator] What a day.
You never know who a fella
will meet when he's looking
for a helicopter.
It's Barbara Anne Scott.
(purrs)
The world's champion
figure skater.
- [Joel] She's the
Cher of her time.
- [Crow] "Ooh,
jimminy," thinks Johhny,
"if only I could get a
ride in one of those."
- [Narrator] Johnny does
find a real airplane,
and gets his ride.
- [Servo] Johnny thinks
Amelia Earhart seems like
a nice lady.
- [Narrator] They take
a spin on Lake Ontario,
to watch the start of the
International Speed Boat Race.
- [Servo] Whoa, Johnny
realizes he's in over his head.
- [Crow] Johnny is irresponsibly
put into a dangerous
speedboat without a life jacket.
- [Servo] For the first
time in his young life,
Johnny knows real fear.
(imitates screaming)
- [Joel] Johnny's hydro-plane
disintegrates on impact.
- [Crow] Johnny's spirit
is completely broken.
- [Narrator] By now the
spring in Johnny's step
is nearly gone.
- [Servo] (singing)
Boy for sale,
he's going cheap!
- [Narrator] There's just
so much a guy can take.
- [Servo] Johnny realizes
what a lie his life has been.
- [Narrator] Right now,
Johnny wants his mother.
Perhaps Olsen and Johnson,
the Hellzapopin boys
can cheer Johnny up.
- [Crow] Yeah, but if
you've seen their act,
you know that's not likely.
- [Narrator] Johnny
wants no part of them.
- [Joel] Johnny's got taste.
- [Narrator] But there's
tricks to every trade.
And the Hellzapopin
boys are tops.
Even a very tired and hungry
Johnny is able to laugh.
- [Servo] Laugh, laugh,
it's funny, laugh!
- [Narrator] Finally, a
friendly policeman takes Johnny
to a building he hadn't
planned on seeing.
- [Joel] (imitating
child) Let me out!
Attica, Attica!
- [Narrator] There are
350 acres of ground in
Exhibition Park.
And mom and pop have
covered every single acre
looking for Johnny.
- [Servo] Did I tell
you to have this baby?!
- [Narrator] They've
looked everywhere.
Everywhere but one place.
- [Crow] Their own hearts.
- [Narrator] He's about so high.
- [Servo] (imitating
Woman) Well, yes, there was
a Mr. Barty here.
(all clap)
- [Servo] Mommy had a little
vacation while you were lost.
- [Joel] Yeah, right,
play it up big in public,
that's right.
- [Crow] (imitating child)
And I met Joe Louis,
and the Prime Minister.
- [Joel] Yeah, whatever.
- [Narrator] Johnny fell asleep
on his father's shoulder,
he had managed to stay awake
just long enough to see
the beginning of the fireworks.
- [Joel] At home.
- [Crow] Johnny's parents
blamed each other and never
trusted again.
Goodnight.
- [Narrator] Pleasant
dreams, Johnny.
- [Servo] So long, sucker.
- [Crow] Let this be
a warning, to you.
(upbeat music)
(bass)
Hey, there's a Mingus among us.
(chuckling)
- [Joel] Oh, you know I
got the nicest rebel set
for my wedding, it's so nice.
Oh, yeah, it's reasonable.
- [Crow] Yusef Lateef,
I-sef Lateef, let's call the
whole thing off.
- [Servo] Man, I wish I
could afford a trap set man.
Man.
- [Joel] Oh, I never
go down to the Village,
they're too nutty down there.
- [Robots] Oh, yeah, oh sure.
- [Servo] Wigged out.
- [Crow] Looking very relaxed,
Adolf Hitler on vibes.
- [Joel] (imitating woman)
Cigar, cigarettes, Camus,
Sartre, Ernst,
alienation, Vitchenstein.
(exclaim)
Wow, close, that was close.
(scatting)
- [Crow] Hey, it's
Fisher and Spasky.
- [Servo] (singing) One night
in Bangkok makes a strong
man crumble!
- [Joel] Boy, those
rebels really go through
the Swiss Miss.
- [Crow] You know this is
the hippest Red Lobster
I've been to.
- [Servo] Ah shit,
here she comes again.
(sigh)
(scatting)
- [Joel] Oh, waitress?
Um, excuse me,
could we get some,
(whistles)
Uh.
Forget it.
(scatting)
- Spraying perfumes of
France upon this beat.
Fleeing atoms of rose,
(snoring)
upon this pair.
Stew oceans of lotions,
and liquid commotions.
Put cologne on the
beards of each lamb.
- [Crow] Oh, that's profound.
Check please.
- Oh, King.
- Hey!
- [Crow] Hey, what do you
want, I'm a character actor!
- Good evening, Mr. T.
- [Servo] Hiya, Mr. B.
- I got a sales report to make.
- Please, Sidney.
It's Mr. Johnson's move.
- [Crow] They're having
a goatee staring contest.
- [Servo] Let's
talk, we never talk.
- I'll have to take your queen.
- How true.
- [Crow] Sorry
about that, chief.
- Check.
And mate.
- [Joel] Hey, you
knocked my block off!
- You win, Mr. Tucker.
- [Servo] Mr. Drucker?
- Twelve minutes.
Perhaps you'll have
better luck next time.
- [Crow] Ah, let's play
Chutes and Ladders next time.
- [Joel] Milk money.
- Don't you ever lose
one of them setoos?
- Rarely, if ever.
- [Servo] Thanks
for asking though.
- And you must be a
virtuous-oso as they say?
- Yes and no, I merely make
sure that my antagonists
are bad chess players.
- [Joel] You're hard to talk to.
- Your report, Sidney.
- Oh, twelve watches.
That comes to an
interesting $325.
- Good hunting.
- [Crow] Boss, why are
you in your pajamas?
- The waitress you
pinched, Sidney.
- Oh, Mr. T, that's
how I express myself.
- [Joel] Express this.
- Quite true, but
this one is new here.
I haven't pinched
her myself yet.
(all groan)
- As you say, Mr. T.
Good hunting.
- Sidney.
- [Joel] Bite me.
- Are you beat?
- Oh, sure man, cool,
way out and long gone,
as they say.
- [Servo] Heh, being sarcastic.
- Fiddlesticks, you want
things and it shows.
- You want things
yourself, Mr. T.
Money, dames, and et cetera.
Why, you own this joint
and you work at it.
You even sprouted a mop.
- [Crow] Don't ever say that.
- When in Rome,
Sidney, do the Romans.
Get these three gentlemen here
tonight, after closing time.
- Then we're ready to move?
- We are, indeed.
- [Servo] Tell 'em
to bring boxes.
- George Leland.
You kidding?
- I never kid.
- But Leland's nothing
but a wild, young punk.
- [Crow] He's my
wild young punk.
- He's also the best
rifle shot I know.
I believe it's the only thing
military school taught him.
- [Joel] His name's Oswald.
- Ray Milland.
John Mapes?
That hamola?
- [Joel] Come on,
they're my friends.
- As you say,
Sidney, that hamola.
- [Crow] We have nothing
to fear but fear itself.
Eleanor.
- [Servo] Hey, I can't
help it, I'm the Fonz, huh?
Yeah.
- [Joel] Mm, I hate
character actors.
- Kate, I am a gentleman.
- [Woman] That I'll try.
- [Crow] Oh, great, another
oily, unlikeable character.
- If you strike me again.
- [Woman] So you
may lose your arms.
If you strike me,
you are no gentleman.
- [Joel] It's Miss Hathaway.
- [Woman] And if no
gentleman, why then, no arms.
- A herald, Kate.
Oh, put me in thy books.
- [Woman] What is your crest?
A cock's comb?
- [Joel] A Henry Miller.
A Henry Miller.
- [Joel] Oh, wait a minute
it's a little late for
acting lessons, they
started filming already.
- You're home kinda
late, Jeannie.
- [Joel] Yes, master.
- It was a last minute
rush at the drive in.
One of the girls didn't show up.
- [Crow] So?
And?
- [Servo] She's dressed
like Jack LaLanne.
- What difference
does it make, anyway?
- Oh, I just hate to see you
working so hard, that's all.
- [Servo] Well then get a job.
- Then look the other way.
- [Joel] (whispers) Ouch.
- [Crow] Murray, use a coaster.
- You know I can do
without cracks like that.
- I'm sorry.
- I know it's
rough on you honey.
- [Joel] I'll get a new shirt.
- Oh, Johnny, how much
longer are we gonna wait
for that break?
- Well it can happen any day.
- Well it hasn't happened for
the last year and a half now.
(all exclaim)
- I've gotta be seen around.
- [Jeannie] Where in
that beat coffee house?
(exclaim)
- What do you expect me to do?
Make a fast $70, $80 a week?
- That's 70, 80 a week, faster
than you're make it now.
- [Joel] Oh, that hurt.
- You used to have faith in me.
- [Crow] Did I?
When?
- I used to have faith in
lots of things, Johnny.
Love conquers all.
- [Servo] That is such a lie!
- 20 room house in Beverly
Hills, with a free form
swimming pool.
- [Crow] You know if you'd
pick up a few more shifts
you could move there.
- I don't believe in
any of it anymore.
- [Joel] Say hello
to the folks, Suzie.
- And I don't think that
you really do, either.
- It's all going to come true.
It's got to.
The law of averages.
- [Servo] I'm
average, I'll make it.
- That law doesn't seem
to work for us, Johnny.
- Hey, come here.
- [Crow] (imitating woman) Ow,
your implant inflated again.
(phone rings)
- I'll get it.
- [Joel] Saved by the bell.
- [Servo] (imitating woman)
Go ahead, answer the phone
Montgomery Clift.
- [Joel] Oh, this must be
that guy from pomade calling.
- Hello?
Sidney?
Yeah?
Bernie!
- [Crow] How's Bridgett!?
- Hey, it's about time
you gave me a call.
- [Servo] Giant bird
suit, eight bucks a week?
- Producer wants to meet me?
Tonight?
I'll be over like
a guided missile.
- [Crow] Only
bigger, and dumber.
- Baby, this might be it.
- Well, who was it?
- Bernie, my agent.
- [Servo] Brillstein?
- Set up a meeting for me
tonight at twelve o'clock,
with a Broadway producer.
- [Servo] Show called
"Moose Murders."
- That late at night?
- Oh, honey you
know show business,
why if the guy wants
to meet me at midnight,
so I'll meet the
guy at midnight.
Aw, come on, how
'bout dinner, huh?
- [Servo] Bring bologna.
- Hey, you know the old saying,
"A hungry actor
never gets a job."
- [Servo] Never heard that.
- [Joel] She's not buying it.
- [Crow] Last night was Joe
Papp, then it was Harold Prince,
I'm sick of it, sick!
- [Servo] Well back
to Junior Jumble.
Gotta go.
- [Crow] Backed with Rose Marie.
(electronic noises)
(whistling)
- It came it came!
Hey, you guys!
Servo, Joel!
It came it came it
came, open it up.
- Hey, Crow what is this?
- Well, hah, you see,
uh, four to six weeks ago
I ordered a series of
acting lessons on records
from the So You Want To
Act Institute Of Acting,
just like in the movie.
- Oh, lucky!
- They came.
- Hey did you order those
from those Sally Struthers
commercials where she goes,
"Do you wanna make more money?
"Sure, we all do."
- No.
- It says, "co-starring
with Scott Baio, you."
Okay, let's see here,
we got scenes from
"Charles in Charge,"
scenes from "Happy Days,"
we got scenes from
"Blansky's Beauties,"
scenes from "Who's
Watching The Kids,"
and scenes from
"Joanie Loves Chachi."
- Yes!
Oh, I decided against
the deluxe edition which
included scenes from
his movies, "Zapped,"
"Bugsy Malone," of
course you knew that,
and "The Boy That
Drank Too Much,"
I just didn't think I
was ready, and I thought
it would give me
something to work towards.
- What do you know?
- Okay, it says here
that for this scene,
I'm Joanie.
- [Voice On Record] Hey, Joanie.
- Hey, Chachi!
Uh, no, no, no,
that's not right.
I'm sorry can we take it from
the top, everyone, please?
Thank you.
- [Voice On Record] Hey, Joanie.
- Hey, Chachi.
Hey, Chachi!
Oh, excuse me, but just what
exactly is the subtext here?
Is "hey" combative
or interrogative, or
just conversational?
- Well, it sounds like an
affectionate acknowledgement
to me.
- Well, remember Crow, at this
point in Joanie and Chachi's
relationship they're
newlyweds and they have this
entire history together from
their years on "Happy Days"
so there's also that dynamic.
And they're struggling
with Chachi's fledgling
singing career.
- True and Joanie is also
trying to cope with the fact
that all their
female fans see her
brand new husband Chachi
as a hunky heartthrob.
- Precisely.
Prima donna.
- Hey, Chachi.
- Crow, you got it.
- Really?
- Yeah!
- Think so?
- Yeah, we'll be
right back, wow.
- Guys I'm gonna need a big
hug after rehearsal today.
- You are so tense.
- Me next.
(bouncy music)
(humming)
- [Servo] Hey look,
you know who that is?
- [Crow] No, who?
- [Servo] Give you a hint,
I sing whenever I
sing, whenever--
- [Crow] Oh no!
- [Servo] Yep, yep, yep.
- [Joel] Hey, the
cops ate my Chiclets.
- [Servo] Hey, how come
I don't even know you
and you keep bailing me out?
What gives?
- [Crow] Hey Vern!
- [Servo] Hey, Ernest does
a nickel up at Attica.
- How'd you get into the act?
- [Crow] I replaced Gummo.
- I bailed you out.
- [Servo] I'm your
guardian angel.
- Why?
- Mr. Tucker wants to see
you tonight after closing.
- [Crow] To strike the set.
- What for?
Doesn't he know that my
mother won't give me a dime?
Unless I straighten up
and go live on that lousy
ranch her third
husband gave her?
- Mr. T. just wants to make
you a business proposition.
- Me?
That's a laugh.
(fake chuckle)
- Mr. Tucker don't appreciate
laughing, so you just
be there.
- [Voice] Hey Leland!
- [Servo] Love that Bob!
(exotic music)
- [Joel] Hey what's his deal?
Oh, it's a woman.
- [Servo] You know guys,
if this is what being Beat
was all about, I'd rather
be a shallow post-Boomer.
Like you.
- [Joel] Hey.
- [Servo] Sorry.
- [Crow] Oh, it's a
Jules Pfieffer cartoon.
(making noises)
- [Joel] Hey, it's Olive Oyl.
- [Crow] Oh, Popeye!
- [Servo] Maybe we shouldn't
have gotten rid of the TV, huh?
- [Joel] Oh, I get it,
it's a Sadie Hawkins dance.
- [Servo] There's a painting
of Marty Allen back there.
- [Crow] Hello dere!
- [Joel] Oh, yeah, I need
liquor to deal with this
weird action.
- [Servo] It's kinda like
beatnik twister, huh?
- [Joel] Twisted sister.
- [Crow] The forbidden
dance of Laura Petrie.
- [Joel] Hey, the more I drink
the more talented you become.
- [Servo] They remind
me of Fred and Ginger.
- [Crow] Yeah, Fred
Travelina and Ginger Baker.
- [Servo] Boom, zing.
- [Joel] Hi, honey I'm...
Oh, my God.
- [Servo] I told you kids
no parties while I'm gone!
- [Crow] Uh, I've come
to look at the apartment.
- Hiya, Ryan.
You're pretty far out, I'd say.
- Far out and floating.
Just received the seventh
rejection slip on my novel.
- Congratulations.
- [Joel] Oh no, you
means it didn't sell,
it's a bad thing.
- You and me gotta make
some conversation where it's
a little more quieter.
- [Joel] You know all
these people are in
middle management now.
- You know what they
say about my book?
- [Crow] It sucked?
- They say it stinks.
- [Servo] Smell it,
see if you agree.
- You know the funny part about
it is, that they're right?
- Eh, what do you
care what they think?
- A year of my life went
into that stinking book.
- Writin' books
is for egg heads.
Mr. T.'s got a better idea.
- T.?
Tucker.
- The same.
Sober up and be at the coffee
house after closing tonight.
- [Joel] My three sons go Beat.
- [Servo] All of them?
- There's no place
else I got to go.
- [Crow] Don't get
no better than this.
- [Joel] Theo Bikel?
This must be 200 Motels.
- [Servo] Wonder how I could
make my life more depressing.
Oh, try this place.
- [Crow] It's the
devil's workshop.
- [Servo] Hey, there he is.
- [Joel] Uh, character
actor to see you, sir.
- Grab a chair,
it's on the house.
- Thanks.
- You cats more or
less acquainted?
- Yeah.
- Then we can
start from scratch.
- [Crow] Can I start you
off with some appetizers?
- Too bad we ain't got no
floor show for you gents,
but once Mr. T. goes into
his filibuster you ain't
gonna miss the
dancing girls at all.
- [All] Shut up.
- Not that we ever
get much romantics
in these here surroundings.
- Sidney, I don't dig you,
all this chopper music
but no tune.
- You know what the trouble
with you beat guys is?
- [Servo] You're so '50s.
- Supposin' you enlighten us?
- You don't talk
English very good.
- Come on, Tucker didn't
get us over there to improve
our speech.
- [Servo] Ernest Hemingway?
- Not your speech, gentlemen.
But perhaps your finances.
- [Joel] Pyramid game?
- The man is
talking about bread.
talking about money.
- [Crow] Get your paws off
me you damn dirty beat!
- You three gentlemen have
been among my steadiest
customers, I've had
opportunity of studying you
closely.
- Are you writing the
great American novel?
- Hardly.
- [Joel] Well actually I'm
doing a Northern Exposure
spec script.
- Nor am I casting a play.
Nor attempting to furnish
psychological guidance
to a poor little rich boy.
- Alright, alright, you've
told us what you're not doing.
Now would you mind telling
us what you are doing?
- Not at all.
- [Joel] I'm reading
for Mel Brooks tomorrow.
- I'm preparing with
your cooperation,
to steal a $1,000,000.
- [Joel] Eleven.
- You say steal?
- Do you know anyone who's
giving away $1,000,000?
- [Servo] Ed McMahon?
- Except Uncle Sam, of course.
- [Crow] Ha, I don't get it.
- You're talking about
some sort of crime.
- What's in a name?
A writer of some
ability once remarked,
"A rose by any other name,
would still have thorns."
- [Servo] I think
you're misquoting.
- I need a drink.
- [Tucker] Certainly, Karen?
- [Joel] Did you call me Karen?
- What I wanna know
is why'd you pick us?
I mean, us three?
[Crow] I saw your audition tape.
- Because none of your are
Beat, you're merely beaten.
You're not detached,
you're unemployed.
You're not dispassionate,
you're afraid,
scared.
- [Joel] Uh, can I still
get an omelet or something?
- [Crow] She just
put her brain in.
- Bring drinks for the
gentlemen, my dear?
- Alright, Mr. Tucker.
- [Crow] (imitating woman) What
do I look like, a waitress?
Oh, oh, I am.
- In exchange for a
few days of your lives,
I'm offering each
one of you $200,000.
- [Crow] Okay, three.
- Money enough for you
to forget you can't act,
- [Joel] Hey, you're
in this film too, bud.
- Perhaps start
reading good ones.
For you to cut loose from your
lovely and wandering mother
so that you may go to
Hell in your own way.
- [Servo] That's kind of a
backhanded compliment, huh?
- [Crow] Thanks for those
quick character sketches, boss.
- Good.
My plan is based on the
interesting fact that if you
take a train from Los
Angeles to New York,
there's a four hour
stopover in Chicago.
- [Joel] It's the SAT caper.
- What's so interesting
about Chicago?
- [Servo] It's my kinda town.
- Any town where you steal
$1,000,000 is interesting.
Before I go into details--
- [Servo] Let's have a song!
- I'm going to impress upon
you that no one can change
his mind.
- [Joel] Okay, you can.
- No one.
Now you notice I didn't
put that as a question.
For the simple reason that
I can buy any of your deaths
for X dollars.
- [Servo] From Sharper Image.
- And X dollars can make
any of you ex permanently.
- [Joel] And that's
exactly what I mean.
- [Crow] Okay, who
ordered the special X?
- [Servo] I had the Dos Equis.
- This isn't what I had in mind.
- I don't have a liquor
license and I don't believe
in breaking small laws.
- [Servo] There are no small
laws, only small criminals.
- As per usual.
- Tomorrow you will get
some presentable clothes,
perhaps a shave.
- [Joel] And a haircut two bits.
- Try to look as though you've
got money enough to travel.
Now the details of
your exact duties,
our meeting place in
Chicago and so forth,
you'll get from Sidney.
Your train tickets will be
picked up here Tomorrow night
at 8:30.
- [Crow] Okay, nine.
- Congratulations on your
association with me in this
magnificent undertaking.
- [Servo] Enjoy your sodas.
- It'll not only be
financially rewarding,
but it might also bring us fame.
Anonymous, of course.
- [Crow] Oh well that...
Huh?
- Now for the details
of the master plan.
- [Servo] First you'll
take this Precious Moments
figure and set it next to
a clock and an ashtray.
Then.
- [Joel] (singing) One
less bell to answer,
one less egg to fry.
- [Crow] Honey,
Kazan wants me for
"On The Waterfront 2:
Electric Boogaloo."
- Johnny?
- [Joel] Uh, are you
in another movie, dear?
It's almost four o'clock.
- I know.
The producer was a windy type.
- [Servo] Kind of an actor
vampire, he can't see his
ego in the mirror.
- [Jeannie] Who is he?
- The producer?
- [Crow] Uh, Joe, uh David.
- Probably has a name.
- Um, Saul Houston.
- [Servo] Big Jew from Texas.
- Never heard of him.
Broadway?
- Well he's a show backer.
He has a syndicate of investors.
He said I was just
right for the part.
- [Joel] The Jethro
Bodine Story?
- Oh, Johnny,
you're not kidding?
- Not at four o'clock
in the morning, I'm not.
Why the devil can't a
woman learn the simple way
of squeezing a
tube of toothpaste?
- [Servo] Doh!
- Well then you did get it, huh?
(bouncy music)
- Where's Mr. Tucker
tonight, Karen dear?
- [Servo] Charles Foster Kane.
- [Crow] And Martha Mitchell.
- How nice.
(exclaim)
- Now people are so
critical of our generation.
- [Joel] People
try to put us down.
- And this way, si vous please.
- [Servo] The
Lockhorns go slumming.
- You behave yourself, I
want them to accept you.
- Accept me?
That's not the idea.
Will I accept them?
- Oh, birds of luna!
- What's that?
Unmask, sir.
- Shh, that's King Invader.
Our poetry laureate.
- Oh, I see,
and he yodels too?
- Oh, Russ.
- Tourists.
- [Servo] Old one eye is back.
- From nothingness
to nothingness.
- [Joel] He's reading the menu.
- [Crow] Nicely done.
- Let's us go on a fool's
errand before they throw
a butterfly net over us.
- [Crow] Hey, man,
that's beautiful!
- We'll have no
intolerant cracks, sir.
I've got my eye on you.
- [Crow] My hungry eye.
- And vice versa.
- And that includes
your language.
- [Servo] Wait, it doesn't
say that in the script
where did that all come from?
- All the five senses.
- [Crow] I always get
the skillet scrambled.
- At least we won't have to
listen to that stuff anymore.
- I happen to like it.
- Well I like old Betsy better.
- That rifle make you
feel any more like a man?
- Smell oh nostril.
(sniffing)
Hear oh ear.
(clapping)
- Bravo, majesty!
- Thank you, oh square.
- [Joel] Hey that would
make a great term for
someone who's not very hip.
- [Crow] Yes it would.
- [Servo] (imitating woman)
Thank you, Mr. Cooper.
I think he's doing uh,
Krepp's Last Ate here.
- A headbutt, it has no content.
- [Crow] Much like this film.
- The brain is missing.
- It's been missing all night!
- [Joel] Do you mind if
we dance with your date?
- Careful with him!
- [Servo] Uh, could we get
our order to go, please?
- Oh, King, we enjoyed
it, truly we did.
- [Crow] My husband's
very hip at home.
- I am bugged.
- [Servo] God of facial hair.
- Beyond recall.
(clapping)
- [Joel] Irwin Corey,
ladies and gentlemen,
Irwin Corey.
- So sorry.
- [Crow] What are
you telling me for?
I'm Lyle Wagner.
Aren't I?
- [Joel] Maybe not.
- Hail, the noble
thespian has arrived.
- [Servo] Hey, I'm as
hetero as the next guy.
- Got the tickets?
- No, but they're here.
- Tucker left them with
Miss IQ before he took off
for Chicago with Sidney.
- Well?
What happened?
- She won't part with them
'til the stroke of 8:30.
- She takes Tucker's
words rather literally.
- Did I see you
adulter, adulterating,
oh, spiking that Coke?
- [Joel] Cut cut!
- Cough medicine.
Four out of five New York
doctors recommend it.
- Oh, really.
- [Crow] Ah, what a comeback.
- Karen.
- Yes?
- What about the tickets?
- You'll get them at 8:30.
- But it is 8:30.
- [Servo] Somewhere
in the world.
- It is 8:10, precisely.
- Karen.
- [Joel] I'll have
the chicken wings.
- Yes, John?
- Where'd you get
that pretty watch?
- Oh, dear Sidney sold it to
me, at a great personal loss.
- I'll bet.
Well it's not working.
- Huh?
- [Crow] My wrist?
Oh, it still works, see?
- [Joel] Come in.
- [Servo] No wonder it's
been 8:10 for three days.
- I'll never trust that
Sidney again, that, that,
h-e-a-l.
- [Crow] She's Danielle Quayle.
- Now would you mind
giving us the tickets?
It really is 8:30, you know?
- [Servo] Can we have
the T-I-K-I-T-Z please?
- Alright.
But, turn the other way.
- [Joel] Um, waitress, could
we order over here, please?
- [Crow] Hey, while
you're in there,
can I have a newspaper?
- Here.
- [Servo] Thanks.
Hey, they're all warm and wet.
- [Crow] Um, can
I have my check,
I mean can I bring
you your check?
- You'll have lots
of time for that.
Eventually.
- [Servo] Well that's a, huh?
- [Crow] Traveling along,
footloose and fancy free.
- [Servo] Thank you
for not smoking.
- Mr. T.?
- [Crow] Move over.
- I'm puzzled, kinda.
- [Crow] If there
was only one gunman.
- It's them creeps.
- Creeps?
- [Servo] You know, committee
to reelect the president.
- I just simply don't get it.
Here you form up a masterpiece,
and then with all the
expert pros available
and on tap,
you hire them creeps.
Rank amateurs.
- [Joel] I trust
Howard Hunt, come on.
- That's exactly
the crux of my plan.
- [Servo] Uh, don't
say crux, please?
- I excite the sleeping
ambition of half talented men.
- [Crow] Thank you, sir.
- Giving each of them a
glimpse of the promised land.
The prospect of an hour
of glory to lift them
out of their drab and
hopeless swamp of mediocrity.
- [Crow] You're hard
to talk to, sir.
- Once inspired by this
last chance to excel,
the creep, as you so
poetically put it,
will go on the mission with
zeal and a single purpose
unmatched even by the
most expert and practiced
criminal.
- [Crow] So, Hardee's
okay with you?
- That my good Sidney
is the alpha and omega
of my theory.
The beginning and the
end of my psychology of
directing the
masterpiece of crime.
- [Crow] You know Burger
King has a drive-through.
Nespas?
- Who's he?
- Another creep.
- [Crow] My boss, always coming
up with phrases like that.
- [Servo] It's the flying nun!
- [Crow] It's Vertigo!
- [Servo] It's Roman
Holiday, and much much more.
- [Joel] Now after shopping
we'll get some lunch
then it's off to the Robert
Hall store for some shoes.
- [PA] Southern Pacific
Sunset arriving on track four.
- [Servo] The remaining pizza
will go on sale for 15 cents.
- [Crow] Well let's see,
Rubber Fantasy, Latex World,
Butt Biters, and
Newsweek, that'll do.
Here's something for you.
- [Servo] Lee Harvey
Oswald on vacation.
- [PA] Union Pacific Challenger,
leaving on track five,
loading at gate number two.
- [Crow] Visit the
off world colonies.
- [Joel] Just burped
up a little egg salad,
oops.
- [Servo] Nobody said
anything about a dome liner.
- [Joel] This is like
the last scene from
"The Untouchables."
- [Crow] Oh, it's
the Cotton Club.
- [Servo] Oh, it's
Narrow Margin.
- [Joel] No, it's Murder
On The Orient Express.
- [Crow] Runaway Train.
- [Joel] It's
Strangers On A Train.
- [Servo] No it's the
Cassandra Crossing.
- [Crow] Silver Streak.
- [Joel] Maybe it's Murder
On The Orient Express,
maybe, did somebody,
oh I said that.
(bouncy music)
Wow you know that
Chicago's a real nice city.
- It's quintessentially
American.
- Oh, okay, yeah.
Well, let's pretend, how
about if we had a four hour
layover like the rebels
in today's experiment,
what would you guys do, Gypsy?
- Oh, I'd go to the Medford
outlet store and shop.
- Uh, Gypsy I don't think
they have a Medford outlet
store in Chicago.
But you could got to
Watertower Place and shop.
- Okay.
- Joel, the first thing I'd do,
this is Chicago after all,
I'd burst through the main
door of the continental
bank building,
wielding my tommy gun,
shouting instructions over
the din of the terrified
screams.
Yes, I would take hostages.
I would demand, and receive,
unbreaking media coverage
of my senseless mayhem.
Negotiations would
drag on for three hours
before breaking down.
Then I'd start tossing
out bodies at seven minute
intervals, oh, better
get back to the train.
You?
- Oh, I'd probably head out
to King Richard's Renaissance
Festival out in
Gurney, Illinois,
probably get a leather mug
or something like that.
(chuckling)
Well you know then I'd
head down to Wrigley field
and hang out with
the bleacher bums,
probably drink beer out of it
or something cool like that.
- You'll want to call ahead
and make sure the game's not
sold out, Joel.
Well, anyway, here's my plan.
Joel, I'd be equipped with a
good pair of walking shoes,
starting at Union Station
I'd head east on Van Buren
across the river,
perhaps viewing one
of the intricate lift
bridges in action.
My heart would race as I
approach the world famous loop,
named for the loop formed
by the elevated train
or, L, as it circles
the downtown area.
It would be Tuesday,
so my admission is free
at the art institute.
My uncle's membership
card gets me into the
member's cafeteria, where
I would dawdle over a
delicious fruit cocktail.
Then I'd stroll down
Michigan Avenue,
doesn't cost a dime to
gaze in wonder at the elite
shops of the magnificent mile.
Oh, no thanks ma'am,
just window shopping.
The new Komisky park
beckons warmly from
Halstead and 35th,
the outfield bleachers are
a great value and always
exciting, White Sox promise
to be a force in the
American League West
for years to come.
Finally,
thank goodness
for my student ID,
I finish up with
the Art Institute,
the Shed Aquarium, Lincoln Park,
and Evanston.
- Uh, sure seems like
a lot of walking.
- Oh, but remember I have a
good pair of walking shoes.
Oh, but look, we still
have a little time.
- Oh boy.
- Sir George Salty and the
Chicago Symphony Orchestra
the very definition
of world class music.
(alarm buzzes)
- Oh we got movie side!
(excited chatter)
(whirring)
- [Crow] Science and Industry
museum has this coal mine
exhibit.
- [Joel] Alright, alright, geez.
- George.
- Introduce me and I
won't tell your wife.
- [Johnny] This is my wife.
- [Servo] No I mean the
woman I saw you with, oof.
- [Johhny] George Leland.
- [George] How do
you do, Mrs. Mapes?
Going to Chicago?
- Uh, New York.
- [Servo] Oh, Miss
Marple is on the case.
- Drinks are on me.
- No thank you.
I'll think I'll turn in.
Why don't you have one
with Mr. Leland, darling.
- Alright, baby, sleep tight.
- [Joel] And don't
look at my stuff.
- [Crow] I'm going to go
see if the three stooges
are doing a routine.
- [Joel] Hmm, seat's warm.
- His wife.
- [Servo] Introduce
me to this fella
and I won't tell your wife.
- What's the idea
of bringing her?
- It was her idea.
- Does Tucker know
you brought her?
- I don't blame you.
If it was my wife, I'd
bring her along too.
- [Joel] Take it back!
- She'd better not.
- Mr. Leland?
- [Servo] We'll be pulling
into Hooterville soon.
- [Porter] May I see
your ticket, please?
- [Crow] Alfred
Hitchcock in drag.
- I'm a great fan
of your mother's.
- [Joel] Thanks, dad.
- Understand she's coming home.
- Well you probably know
more about that than I do.
- Thank you, Mr. Leland.
- [Joel] Hi, Al, nice dress.
- Even with the booze I still
don't care for you company.
- [Servo] What did I say?
- What's wrong with him?
- [Crow] He's got
an upset tummy.
Charmed I'm sure.
- [Servo] Don't wait
up for me, Irma.
(train horn blows)
We will return to
Von Ryan's express.
- [Crow] Chicago, hog
butcher to the world!
(humming)
(mock muffled) Hey, let us
outta here, let us outta here.
- [Servo] Max and 99 should
be here by now, Larraby.
Larraby.
- [PA] Chicago, Rock
Island, and Pacific.
From Joliet, Rock Island,
Des Moines, Omaha,
Burlington, and
Colorado Springs.
- [Crow] And Coca banga.
- [Servo] Can't believe we
didn't have our tickets,
they really enforce that.
- [Joel] Hi.
- [Servo] Gee, I can't wait
to see the Statue of Liberty.
- [Joel] It's Chicago, dear.
- [Servo] I see you brought
your ventriloquy doll here.
- Look honey, I've gotta
see about the play.
Meet me back here
at train time, okay?
- [Crow] (imitating
woman) Oh, you have to go
to the bathroom?
- John, why can't I go with you?
- It's not a social meeting.
Well you might call it politics,
you see this man can put
in a good word for me.
- [Joel] You're
dragging me down.
- You're not ashamed
of me, are you?
- Oh, of course, darling.
It's just that I feel a
bit self conscious making
a pitch with anyone
listening in.
- [Joel] You're a boat anchor!
- Me listening in?
John I'm your wife!
- [Servo] I'm glad you
brought that up honey,
technically you're my wife, but.
- Now be a good girl, huh?
Here.
Go to the pump room and
have yourself a good time.
- [Crow] Get some change
and play as many video games
as you want.
- Sure, I'll have a ball.
- [Joel] And a dollar, thanks.
- [Servo] Why is she
wearing a fishing hat?
- Sweetheart.
- [Crow] This is a
silver certificate.
- Good luck.
- [Joel] Criminey, this one.
- [Servo] Uh, Ed,
genuflect, please.
- [Joel] Phil can I
see you in my office?
- [Servo] You blew it, Phil.
- [Crow] I still like you.
- [Servo] Damn, I
gave her my last buck.
- [Crow] Oh, Empire State
Building on Nutrisystem.
- [Servo] No, no,
no, Tribune Tower.
(scatting)
Geez, the donuts are
cheap in this town, man.
Oh, hey, your coat's
in the door, hey!
- [Crow] Oh, they're draining
the blinker light fluid.
- [Servo] Hey, I'm not half bad.
- [Joel] What is he
getting ready for
the renaissance festival?
- [Crow] Here's where the
den will be, and my room.
- [Servo] So, uh, how's this
supposed to get 'em $1,000,000?
- [Crow] The hat squad.
- That milk oughta
be quite a shock
to Ray's flask.
- [Joel] Yeah, don't
cry over this, okay?
- [Crow] Is this a
road runner thing?
- Until it hits
that spot exactly.
- [Servo] Uh, the beginning
or the end of that spot?
Uh, Ed?
- [Joel] So uh, just behind
this grassy knoll here, boss?
Okay.
- On time to the second, Mr. T.
Now we must hope the
armored car is also on time.
- [Crow] Super Dave.
- We must also the take
at the racetrack was up to
its usual high standards.
- [Servo] Huh, can't hear ya?
- That's a very
nice high standard.
- Take the car on up.
- [Servo] Boing.
- [Crow] Suddenly it's
"From Russia With Love."
- [Servo] "The Day
of the Jackal."
"The Manchurian Candidate."
"The Dead Zone."
"The Man Who Knew Too Much."
"The Sugarland Express."
"Foul Play."
- [Crow] I'm gonna kill
that milk to impress
Jodie Foster.
- [Joel] Tonight's episode,
Milk, it does a body dead.
- [Servo] "Dirty Harry."
"The Parallax View."
"Ironsight," the pilot.
Suddenly, I on hill
lived a lonely goat.
I love my job, never think
I have to get out to work
in the morning, you
know what I mean?
- [Joel] Oh, we don't
have to see this.
- [Crow] Chief, that's sick.
Mrs. Webb, you're backing up,
that's a one way, Mrs.
Webb, don't pull out.
- [Servo] Huh, what
are the chances?
Someone else spilled milk.
- [Joel] Gentlemen,
spill your milk.
- [Crow] My boss, always
comin' up with nutty schemes.
- [Servo] Buckle up for murder.
- [Joel] Tommy Kirk, assassin.
- [Servo] Geez, I
wish I had my car mix.
Road runner, road runner,
never bothered anyone.
- [Crow] Maybe I can
get on that bizarre show
with John Byner.
- [Servo] The Timex
Marlin, still ticking!
- [Crow] So they're
waiting, then.
- [Joel] Alright,
we'll wait then.
- [Servo] Someone's
tuning a piano.
I'm Ed Bradley and
this is 60 murders!
- [Joel] Something new is
coming to town and George
the milkman's bringing it down.
- [Crow] And now a few
murders with Andy Rooney.
- [All] The get away
chase game, get away!
- [Servo] Get away!
- [Crow] Joe Dogs, not
a very good driver.
Oh, thank God I
had this helmet on.
- [Servo] I'm a mess.
Oh, that's right, I did that.
Shoulda worn a cup.
(chuckling)
Must get to Benny Hill taping.
- [Crow] You okay, ma'am?
Uh, sir.
- [Servo] Yep, first thing
to do to an injured person?
Move 'em.
(siren)
- [Joel] Oh no, I'm
really in trouble now
stay together cheeks,
stay together.
Hello?
- [Crow] Hey, could I
get a ride into town?
- What happened?
- Some dope ran me
right off the road.
- [Servo] That's
part of the plan.
Oh, doh!
- [Crow] Drawing their
guns at a traffic accident?
- You fellas sure came
along at the right time.
- [Joel] That's great, disrobe.
- I don't know where
this guy came from,
but he looks pretty
badly hurt to me.
- You don't have
to worry about him.
Put your hands up.
(dramatic music)
- [Servo] And a
new world record!
- [Crow] Oh, it
really got up there.
- [Joel] Oh man, they
rolled a good humor truck.
- Alright let's go, move.
- [Servo] Oh, you're
in on it too, huh?
Now I get it, no wonder
he had a helmet on.
- [Crow] You guys gonna
finish these sandwiches?
- [Servo] Now, I left the
house today with a long rope,
a medium rope, and a short rope.
- [Crow] Oh, it's a
hap-hap-happy day, toodle-loo.
(whistling)
- [Servo] Oh no, we
robbed a diaper service!
- Lovely, lovely.
- Working like a clock.
A million buck clock.
- Let's move.
- [Crow] But I like
where I'm living.
- [Joel] This is about the
time Superman would show up.
- [Servo] So why don't they
move the car close to the truck?
- A little assistance gentlemen.
- [Joel] Oh, oops I accidentally
tied up one of our gang.
(siren)
- [Crow] Is that us?
- That's it, let's move.
- [Joel] Uh, can I
ride in front, boss?
- [Servo] I'm thirsty,
who's thirsty?
I got a Mountain
Dew, a Diet Coke,
Mr. Pibb.
- [Crow] Hey hand me my Slurpee.
- [Servo] Hey, Wally you need
some shocks on this thing.
Ridin' kinda low.
- [Crow] Ah, the Blue
Ridge Mountains of Chicago.
- [Joel] Hey look, they drove
onto the Timmy and Lassie set.
- [Servo] You shoulda
gone before the heist.
- [Joel] What a rush, they
totally don't know where
we are.
- [Crow] An Ed Asner costume.
- Well we're five
minutes behind schedule,
I suggest speed.
- [Joel] Alright, happy
birthday to me, happy birthday
to me, I shouldn't have.
- [Crow] Heh, he's
building a lean-to.
- [Servo] Mr. Goodbars?
- [Joel] Hey I found
some roots and grubs,
we could survive here for weeks.
- All the guns go
into the hole as well.
- [Crow] Ha, fire
in the hole, heh,
aw never mind.
- [Servo] So uh,
where's this go?
- [Joel] In the hole.
- [Crow] Movie's not over yet
and they're striking the set.
- [Servo] Okay, what about this?
- [Joel] Oh, that
would go in the hole.
- [Servo] Okay.
- [Crow] Let's see
hole, hole, garage sale,
hole.
Hole, salvation army, hole.
- [Servo] So where's
the turtle wax?
- [Joel] In the hole!
- [Crow] Kettle drum?
- [Joel] In the hole.
Hole right?
- That stays with me.
- [Joel] Oh, alright.
- [Crow] Oh, yeah, it's so
easy to find cop appliques.
- [Servo] Where's that going?
- [Joel] In the hole.
- [Servo] Belt, pants,
heck I'm just gonna jump
in the hole.
- [Crow] Uh, could you
look under the hood,
there's some funny
sound comin' out of it.
- [Servo] Tell Zappa
to turn the music down,
Ruth Underwood wants
her vibes back.
- [Crow] Hey be sure to put
that shovel in the hole.
- [Joel] Alright, who wants gum?
- [Robots] I do, I do!
- [Joel] It's in the hole.
- You have exactly 30 minutes
to get back to the train,
gentlemen.
- [Joel] And have your
tickets ready, they're real
strict about that.
Hey, I was supposed to
get the front this time.
- [Servo] But I get car
sick, you don't want that.
- [Joel] Oh.
- [Crow] You idiot, your coat
is stuck in the door again.
- [Servo] I can't get
it out of reverse!
- [Crow] I just don't
understand the rebel part
of this movie.
- [Joel] Well robbing a
bank was pretty rebellious.
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Servo] Used up that
dollar three hours ago.
- [PA] Leaving on track six.
- [Crow] Hey she
got a new head tort.
- [Servo] Um, pardon
me boy, oh forget it.
- [Joel] It looks like
she bought a snare drum.
- What took you so long?
- I made it didn't I?
Come on.
- [Crow] I said have
your tickets ready.
- Hey, Leland!
I'm Jack Simpson,
Chicago Morning Star.
- Why don't you
guys leave me alone?
- [Crow] Mine.
- How about your mother?
There's a rumor Count
Rufina gave her the air.
- Get outta my way.
- Listen, buster.
- [Servo] I hate Irv Cups in it.
- You know you could use
a little more good will
from the press.
- Excuse me.
- [Joel] So anyway I
bought this darling drum
and it's got the snare
and everything, I don't
see why we couldn't.
- [Crow] Hey, it's
Ralph, she's takin'
the Hooterville trolley too.
(exclaim)
- [Servo] The exorcist.
- [Man] All aboard!
- [Crow] Plot point.
- How was your meeting?
- [Crow] Profitable.
- Johnny?
- Oh, meeting?
- [Joel] Why can't Johnny think?
- You don't sound
very enthusiastic.
- It's not very exciting
meeting a playwright.
- Oh, I thought it was
one of the money people.
- Well, he's a rich playwright.
- Oh, what's his name?
- [Servo] Uh, Rich.
- What is this a
cross examination?
- [Crow] Nobody expects
the cross examination!
- [Servo] Oh, sorry.
- Oh, I'm sorry, honey.
- [Joel] I'm a
jerk, you know that.
- I guess my nerves
are on edge a bit.
- [Crow] George Bernard
Shaw was teasing me.
- The, uh, producer's
name, Saul Houston.
- [Servo] Yeah, big
Jew from Tex, oops.
- That's the man you said
you met in Hollywood.
- [Servo] No, it's the
other Saul Houston,
the one, Chicago one.
- Yes, that's right.
Oh, I meant to tell you
honey he flew in yesterday.
- [Joel] He'll never use
the closets in our house.
(bouncy music)
- Excuse me Mr. Miller?
- [Joel] Love Tropic of
Cancer, just had to tell you.
- [Crow] Hey it's Merit Stone!
- [Servo] No it isn't!
- [Crow] Is.
- [Servo] Is not.
- [Crow] Is?
- Oh, you're a writer, eh?
- [Crow] Well, I guess not.
- Set down all the true
to life things I've seen.
- [Joel] You'd throw up.
- But you and me could.
You are a writer aren't you?
- [Servo] Yeah, I write
about the life of the mind.
- Yeah, I suppose so.
- You know everybody I've
told about my memoirs said--
- [Servo] Shut up!
- You should write a book.
- [Servo] Well like I once saw
a woman with an unusual hat.
- Same thing's happened to me.
- I wish I could type.
Say,
here's my card.
50/50 on all my stories, huh?
- [Crow] Thank you,
Mr. Animal Rummy is it?
- Well thanks, Mr. Miller.
- I'll call you.
- Gee, thanks a lot.
- [Joel] I'll bet
he never calls.
- [Servo] Now, let's
see, where was I?
"A screaming comes
across the sky."
- [Radio] As of this hour,
the police have no leads
on the armored car
robbery in Chicago.
- [Crow] Hey, turn it
up, this is my heist.
- [Joel] So, you gals
are in a band, huh?
- [Servo] We're Heart.
- Reverend?
Do you know what I think
is responsible for all
this crime?
- [Crow] Eisenhower.
- I haven't the most
remote idea, sister.
- The people involved.
- [Crow] Art Linkletter,
they all have Art Linkletter
on 'em.
(knocking)
- Who is it?
- [Servo] Just a second.
- [John] John.
- [Servo] Jut a minute I'm
countin' the loot we stole,
oh, sorry didn't say that, nope.
- [Crow] That five
bucks you owe me?
I wanna get some chips.
- [Joel] Art Linkletter?
- Pretty isn't it?
- [Servo] Kinda cute, why?
- What're you doin' with a gun?
- Just keepin' it company.
- What's the matter with you?
Tucker warned us about guns.
- I need a gun to protect
my beautiful money.
- Your money?
- [Crow] It's for
my student loans.
- There's your cut.
Now you get outta here.
- You don't think you're
gonna get away with this?
- The only thing you can
do is yell for the cops.
But you won't do that.
Not with your beautiful wife.
- [Joel] This is not
my beautiful wife.
- [Servo] Yes, I can certainly
see where you'd wanna keep
that money, I'd certainly
side with your part of the
argument here, there's
no doubt about.
- [Crow] This is just like
"Treasure of the Sierra Madre"
only it's not good.
(hum "Star Trek" duel theme)
(grunting)
- [Crow] Now, to return
this to Marshal Fields.
Goodbye, uh, nice
working with you.
- I don't see that
Leland boy anywhere.
- Probably drinking his dinner.
- Oh, Hattie.
You know very well it's
not drinking that got him
into the papers.
- [Joel] Donuts?
- [Servo] Psst, come on,
it's about the heist.
- [Crow] My waist?
- [Servo] No the heist.
- Reverend.
- [Joel] Blue jeans.
You bitch.
- What are you doing with that?
- I just had a
fight with George,
I had to slug him.
- [Servo] It was so freeing.
- Thieves falling out?
- He wanted to keep all
the money for himself.
- I don't want it here.
What about your compartment?
- And have Jeannie find it?
- I don't want it here.
- What would you suggest?
We call the conductor and
have him keep it for us?
- [Joel] You know
I didn't mean that.
- We've gotta talk
some sense into George.
- [Joel] Oh, I can't
stay mad at you,
come on let's hug.
- [Crow] Mickey Mouse!
- [Joel] M-U-R-D-E-R.
- [Servo] Oh I see your
point, but if we do
hide the loot in my room
then the cops might find it
and then we're gonna be.
- [Crow] Oh he's got a
nice round one, doesn't he?
- [Servo] Mm-hmmm
it's Floyd Turbo.
- [Crow] Well, we're
rebels, here's our chance.
Disturb, disturb,
disturb disturb.
- [Servo] We bugging you?
He's a mess.
Chocolate mess.
- [Joel] Go fish.
(sniffs)
- [Crow] Steve.
- [Joel] Yeah, good
thing the carpet's brown.
- You forgot to
mention one thing,
you put a bullet
through his brain.
- All I did was hit him.
- [Servo] With a bullet.
- That's your story.
- I didn't use a gun.
This is the one I took from him.
Take a look for yourself.
- [Joel] Hmm, kids,
shot this guy for you,
ham in fridge, mom.
- Suicide.
- Except that
note's typewritten.
And I've got gun.
- [Crow] I got gun.
- You know whose typewriter
that was written on?
Mine.
The E on my typewrite prints
lower than rest of the letters.
- [Servo] Wow!
- Let's get outta here.
- Yeah.
- No!
- [Servo] No?
- They could trace
that note to me.
- He's tried committing
suicide before.
- [Joel] Did it work?
- You could get rid
of your typewriter.
- That would mean that
only you and I know that
it was murder.
- You're forgetting
someone else.
- [Crow] God knows, Davey.
- Who?
- The murderer.
(laughing)
- [Servo] No, no, no,
it's a social gospel.
I quite agree with
you, sister Crenshaw.
Mine too is a small town.
Yet, somehow in such
Arcadian surroundings,
sin doesn't seem to
be quite so sinful.
- How true, how true.
- [Servo] Traveling
with Gertrude and Alice.
- [Crow] But I still say
that if we hid the loot with
the body that'd be killing
two birds with one.
- Those two men look as if
they'd just seen a ghost.
- How many men are afraid
of ghosts who are not afraid
of the all high.
- You put that very
beautifully reverend.
- [Joel] But, shut up.
- Thank you.
- [Crow] Ow, my knee.
- I think I'd better get
back to Jeannie before she
starts worrying.
- I'll get rid of
the typewriter.
- [Crow] Where's my kiss?
What about my kiss?
Aw, I still suck, I thought
I'd written something
good for a second there.
- [Servo] Gordon Lisch is
gonna give me a really bad
grade for this.
- [Joel] (singing) Summer
breeze, makes me feel fine,
going through the jasmine...
Mind.
- [Servo] As a gift to the
reading public he's throwing
his typewriter away.
Thank you.
- [Crow] Thinks
he's Harry Truman.
- [Servo] I'll just
drop these in the mail.
Ow!
- [Joel] Sorry!
- [Crow] Boy I wish Bret
Easton Ellis would do
that with his typewriter.
- [Servo] So, do
I come here often?
- Very clever, Mr. Miller.
A wise precaution on your part.
- Who are you?
- I'm the Reverend
Basil Cuttingham.
Or should I say
the very reverend.
- You're Tucker.
- [Crow] We just did a
heist together, remember?
- I'm the Reverend Basil
Cuttingham of Pembrough,
New Hampshire.
- [Servo] I believe you
believe that's who you are.
- I should've known you'd
never let that money
get too far away from you.
You're the one
who killed George.
- One less share to disperse.
- [Joel] One less failed to ask.
- And now Mr. Miller.
- [Servo] I'm gonna
shave your mustache.
- There'll be still
another share less.
- [Crow] Cross
and a switchblade.
- You don't have to kill me.
- [Crow] Murder on the
disoriented express.
- I didn't want any
of your damn money!
- [Servo] So, um, what
happened, I don't get it.
- Conductor?
- Yes, ma'am?
- [Crow] I'm lonely.
- Are we on time?
- Yes we are.
- We hate to be late.
- So do we.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have some work to do.
- I think lateness is a defect
in a person's character.
- This train is never late.
Good night.
- [Joel] Gary Busey
after the accident.
- [Servo] Mm, bookends.
- He's a disgrace
to the uniform.
- [Crow] I love a
disgrace to a uniform.
- The air conditioning on
this train is splendid,
but there's nothing like
God's own air to breathe.
- Well maybe so, Reverend.
But it's against regulations.
- [Joel] So out you go.
- Regulations against breathing.
- Have your little
joke, eh, Reverend?
- [Servo] Oh, you make me sick.
- [Crow] Out we go.
- Goodnight, Reverend.
- Goodnight to you sir.
- [Joel] What a dope.
(whirring)
- Joel, we've got our
short stories ready.
Boy I'm so exciting.
Having a writer's
workshop was a great idea.
I may even give up
writing spec scripts
and concentrate solely
on fiction from now on.
- Oh, that's great, Crow.
This could open up a
whole new area of writing
for you to fail in.
- That's not very
supportive, Tom.
- Yeah, well Whatever,
Joel, what made you decide
to have this dumb old
writer's workshop anyway?
- Well it's from this new
creative writing book I got
called, "Writing Down The
Tracks," by Merit Stone,
the conductor in
today's experiment.
- He's not Merit Stone!
- Okay, whatever.
Let's hear your
stories you guys.
- Okay, me first,
me first, me first.
(clears throat)
The vast emptiness of
space lay before me,
the stars in the galaxies
were apart from me,
yet seemed inside me also.
All of my deepest yearnings,
my most profound,
inner-most thoughts,
my striving, aching soul
that longed to love,
and be loved.
All of these things were
reflected in the twinkling
of the stars, the
rising of the moon
as I ventured forth upon--
- Uh, Crow, Crow, listen
that's all very well and good,
but if Merit Stone were here--
- He's not Merit Stone!
- If Merit Stone were here,
he would wonder why
there's no scene where
a ticket gets punched,
and no one has said, "Can
I take your bags, please?"
As far as I can tell, your
story doesn't even involve
a train.
I'm sorry, Crow.
This is gonna need extensive
rewrites if you wanna
please Merit Stone.
Huh, Tom?
- He's not Merit
Stone, thank you.
(clears throat)
(English accent) Stately
plump Pork Mulligan
came down from the
stairwell and laid a razor--
- Hey, you stole that
from Joyce DeWitt!
- Uh, Crow, it's James Joyce,
and whether he stole it or not,
his story has no sense of place,
we have no idea if it
takes place in Massapequa,
Massepequa Park, Amityville,
Koepeg, Lindedhurst,
Babylon,
change at Jamaica for--
- [Servo] That does it.
(growling)
- Can I read my story.
- Sure Gypsy, go ahead.
(clears throat)
- A train leaves a station
at 2:00 PM, going 90 miles
an hour.
Another train leaves another
station going the opposite
direction at 5:00 PM
going 60 miles an hour.
How long before they meet?
- Oh, Gypsy, that is everything
great literature should be.
According to Merit Stone.
- [Servo] He's not Merit Stone!
(bouncy music)
(chatter)
- We could be witnesses.
- Ladies, please.
- [Crow] Ladies,
back me up on this.
- [Joel] Merit Stone,
ladies and gentlemen.
- [Crow] He's not Merit Stone!
- You should have
kept the door shut.
- How'd I know they gon'
be wandering around?
- Well see that no
one else comes in.
- Yes, sir.
- [Joel] I just told you
not to open the door.
- Shocking.
Utterly shocking.
- Well, he tried it before.
This time he made it.
- Tried what before?
- Suicide.
- [Servo] Did it work?
- [Crow] Oh, pound
pastrami, canned kraut,
six bagels, bring home for Emma.
- What makes you
think it was suicide?
- Well, what else would it be?
- Murder.
- [Joel] Well that's an option.
- Why do you say that?
- This note is typewritten.
- Well?
- Where's the typewriter?
- How well'd you
know him, Johnny?
- Who?
- The Leland boy?
- [Crow] Well we dated.
- Casually, why?
- This has been a funny trip.
- [Servo] Yeah, sharing
a train with Gallagher.
- I haven't been
splitting my sides.
- I didn't mean it that way.
- What are you doing?
- What, getting a cigarette.
- [Joel] Hey, don't
take my last cigarette.
- Johnny?
- Here.
- Where'd you get
all that money?
- Stage money.
- [Servo] You're
in Guys and Dolls?
- [Crow] Phil never carries
stage money at home.
- [Joel] It's gonna take me
a few minutes to rationalize
this one.
- [Crow] Ladies and
gentlemen, Merit Stone!
- [Servo] He's not Merit Stone!
- I uh, wired ahead
to the police.
They'll meet the train
to Newark in the morning.
- A sound idea.
- [Joel] Father
Dowling Mysteries.
- Uh, one more thing.
- [Crow] You know I've
always wanted to be a priest,
I've forgiven a lot of
people in the years.
- One of the
passengers is missing.
- Indeed, who?
- That writer in compartment D.
The fellow I gave
all my stories to.
- [Joel] You know, the
guy you pushed off.
- He must have had
a very urgent reason
to jump from a speeding
train, don't you think?
- A very good reason.
- Which was?
- His typewriter.
- [Servo] Hey, Edie Sedgwick.
- [Crow] And then when I
was 19 my skin cleared up,
and that was a good day.
- Jeannie?
- Yes?
- [Joel] Is it almost
my turn to sleep?
- About that money.
- What about it, Johnny?
- [Servo] Well, I
got it selling grit.
- I've been lying to you.
- [Crow] I'm not really
a submarine captain.
- Where did you get it?
- [Joel] Caddying.
- From the Chicago robbery.
- [Crow] The hydraulic wife.
- What are you saying?
- I helped steal it.
- [Servo] You got a job?
Oh, I love the Chicago robbery.
- Oh, Johnny, no.
- It seemed to be the
answer to everything.
I wanted to give you everything.
- [Crow] Well, not everything,
we don't have the closet
space but, you know what I mean.
- Oh, Johnny.
- Jeannie,
George Leland didn't
commit suicide.
I might've had the guts to
go through with the robbery,
but I can't take murder.
- Murder?
- [Joel] Well I guess
this puts my card game on
Wednesday night in perspective.
- [Servo] I love it when
my plans come together.
Next week on The Rebel Set.
(train horn)
- [Crow] A love scene.
- [Joel] No.
No tunnel.
- [Servo] (singing)
New ark, new ark!
- [Crow] I'm a cop, I commute.
- [Joel] I work the
day watch on the 722,
Long Island Railroad,
my name's Reading.
- Wait here.
Keep all the other cars closed.
- [Crow] I like your uniform.
- [Servo] Oh, this'll be fun.
- The police are coming aboard.
- [Joel] They're coming
to take me away, ha ha.
- I'm going with you.
- I'd rather you didn't.
- [Crow] They don't
have connubial cells.
- I love you, Jeannie.
- [Servo] It's Cynthia.
- I know you do.
And I'm going with you, Johnny.
All the way.
- [Joel] Oh, and thanks
of being so supportive of
my acting career that I
took to a life of crime.
- Where's the body?
- [Crow] Follow your nose.
- [Servo] Oh, hey,
it's a picnic casket.
- [Crow] Maybe they think
they're pickin' up Moses.
- [Joel] Maybe it's more
of a light summer casket,
I would say.
- [Servo] Okay, who wants
his Visa card, here?
I have no face.
- [Joel] It's officer not
appearing in this scene.
- You wait here.
My name's John Mapes.
I've got something
to tell the police.
- Let him in, Pat.
- [Crow] Yeah, let's
have a few more people
to kick around the crime scene.
- George Leland
didn't commit suicide.
- [Servo] I did.
- We know that.
You trying to
confess his murder?
- No, sir.
But the both of us were
involved in the Chicago armored
car robbery.
- [Servo] I'm not interested.
Try the next car.
- Are you having
delusions of grandeur?
- I know where the money is.
- [Joel] There's
money in direct sales.
- Why this sudden urge
to tell all, Mr. Mapes?
- Because I've been a fool.
- [Crow] Oops, that
was even more foolish.
- Alright, show me.
- [Servo] And still
I have no face.
- Your wife?
- Yes, sir.
- [Servo] Sorry.
- [Paul] Hey.
- Newark, I'd know it anywhere.
- [Servo] Even if I wasn't
in Newark, I'd know I was
in Newark.
Doing.
- [Joel] You know that
wasn't part of my master plan
but it was just
for fun, you know?
- And thus, did mighty Samson
overcome the Philistine.
- [Crow] By hitting him on
the head with a sitting stick
and wearing a priest costume?
I didn't know that.
- Here's your money.
- [Servo] I hid it
with my negligee.
- [Crow] Uh, could I
take back the confession?
- Who do you think
you're kidding?
- But that's where
we hid the money!
- Yeah, and where did
you hide the killer?
- Tucker!
There's your killer!
- [Detective] Open up, Mapes.
Open up.
- [Servo] Okay,
honey, you go here.
And this'll go there.
- [Crow] Oh, plenty of room now.
- [Joel] Ow, my hands!
(gunshots)
Ow!
- No!
- [Crow] Please, ma'am,
I'm just trying to mow down
your husband in cold blood!
Step back.
- [Servo] Oh, my arches!
- [Joel] 'Kay, I won't
kill your husband.
What a baby.
- [Crow] Let's see, I
put a penny on the track
right about here.
- [Servo] Officer were
you looking for me?
- [Crow] Hey, a penny.
- Come on!
- [Servo] Everybody's doin' it!
(bouncy music)
(singing) A mighty
fortress is a,
a mighty fortress, oh God,
a bulwark never failed me.
- [Crow] It's John Candy!
- [Servo] Hey, that
was John Candy!
A mighty fortress is a, hey.
(scatting)
Oh, sons of God, uh-oh.
- [Crow] Richard Kimble.
Some of us are going to
lunch, you wanna come?
(howling)
Well where do you wanna eat?
- [Joel] Well there was a
really nice muffin shop,
there it is!
- [Servo] Hey,
Wisconsin's the other way.
(dramatic music)
(gunshots)
(whining like injured dog)
- [Servo] It only takes a
spark to get a fire going.
- [Crow] Well maybe Thomas
the Tank Engine will come to
save the day.
- [Servo] From Hollywood,
The Tonight Show starring
Johnny Carson!
- [Joel] Fada hold up, there's
some stuff I wanna confess!
- [Crow] Okay, fada, I
took some Lions mints
and I read "Lolita"
and I liked it.
Please forgive me, okay?
- [Servo] So low,
can't get under it,
so high, can't get over it,
so wide, can't get around it.
- [Crow] Uh, father,
I had impure thoughts
three times last week.
About you!
And I have these doubts you
see, and sometimes I get
angry at people.
- [Joel] You have
the right to remain,
aw forget it.
(gunshots)
- [Servo] With Johnny's guests.
- [Joel] Beatniks,
ladies and gentlemen.
Beatniks.
Hello.
- [Servo] Hello.
- [Crow] Hello.
- [All] Hello?
- [Crow] We should really
get out the calisthenics.
- [Joel] That's funny,
thanks quirky threesome.
- [Servo] Oh, sons of God,
here's holy water,
gather 'round the table.
- [Crow] Now look, father,
you gotta forgive me, see?
E nomine patri.
- [Servo] Whoa, he
can't take it there.
- [Joel] Go in peace, sin
no more, I'm outta here.
- [Crow] Oh, I feel better,
I'm gonna confess
to him more often.
- [Servo] Light penance.
- [Joel] Priest
on a hot tin roof.
- [Crow] Father Mannix.
- [Joel] Amen.
- [Servo] And sings my soul,
my savior God,
how great thou are.
How great thou are.
- [Crow] Father Mannix wait!
- [Joel] Amen.
I said you're forgiven,
now leave me alone!
- [Crow] Now I need some
advice on my marriage,
you're the only one I can
go to with these problems!
- [Servo] The heist
has ended, go in peace.
- [Crow] Ah there's
something you don't
see every day, Chauncy.
- [Servo] What's that, Edgar?
- [Crow] Priest beatin'
the hell out of a guy
in a factory.
(humming)
- [Servo] Can I
use your bathroom?
Thanks.
- [Crow] I'm with him.
Stay together cheeks,
stay together.
- [Crow] He's gotta return
that costume by noon.
- [Servo] Oops.
Oh, I've had dreams like this.
- [Joel] He's nude!
- [Servo] I'm really
steamed at you.
(chuckling)
- [Joel] Nude man.
- [Crow] Okay, look, you're
fired from the caper!
- [Servo] Alright, you two,
marquis of Queensbury
rules, come on.
- [Joel] Who's the
man in the white suit?
- [Crow] Look, there's
a guy we can shoot!
- [Joel] Now he's
beating up a milkman,
he hates people in uniform.
(humming)
- [Servo] Oh, he's hitting
him with vermicelli,
that's cruel.
(humming)
- [Crow] Merry Christmas,
have some tinsel.
- [Servo] For a big guy,
he's a lousy fighter,
he gets beat up by
an elderly priest.
- [Joel] Yeah, he'd lose
a fight with Irene Ryan.
- [Crow] I am in
a state of grace,
leave me alone!
- [Servo] Gangs of
chain wielding priests,
next on Geraldo.
- [Joel] Hey, weren't
you just nude?
- [Crow] Priest be
nimble, priest be quick.
Me too.
- [Servo] At the wine cellars
of Ernest and Julio Gallo.
- [Joel] Bless you, bless you!
- [Crow] Ah, now he's
the Statue of Liberty.
- [Joel] It's him!
- [Servo] Forgive me,
father, for I have murdered.
- [Joel] That is the
biggest sub sandwich I have
ever seen.
Look, his coat is
caught in the door.
- [Servo] Nice basket, Phil.
I love that one.
- [Crow] Hi, what's your name?
- [Servo] I'm too ashamed
to ask you for a ticket.
Tickets, please, tickets.
- [Joel] Hi, honey,
I'm home, kind of.
- [Servo] Why, he's adorable.
- [Crow] Well, he
helped pad out the film,
so he might get off.
- Darling,
what happened?
- Your husband helped
nab the killer.
That'll be in his favor.
Come on, fella.
- [Servo] So, it'll only
be 20-30 years honey,
so let me just say, I'd
take a lover if I were you.
- [Joel] Um, could I have
the checkbook or something?
The keys?
- [Crow] I've never
been to Joliet,
what's it like?
- Oh, what difference
does it make?
Poor little me, I'm not news.
- Just try telling
that to my editor.
- Well, it's really was
because of my darling,
darling boy.
I've come home to be
a real mother to him.
- [Servo] Yeah, that's
fine, can I take your
lunch order now?
- I must confess
I've neglected him.
But now, now the curtain rises
on the bright new horizon.
- [Servo] Horizon.
- A new and lovely life
for just the two of us.
I realize that above all
things, I'm a mother.
- [Crow] Check that.
- And you may quote me on that.
- Well thank you, Miss Leland.
- [Joel] Oh, what a dark
comment on our society.
- [Crow] We've secretly
taken his live son
and replaced him
with this dead one.
Let's watch.
- [Joel] See what
coffee houses can do?
- [Servo] So, uh, all this
happened because Johnny got
lost at the fair?
- [Joel] Well, I guess
I'll have to give this hat
back to Colonel Blake now.
- [Crow] Cream chip
beef, that sounds good.
Wonder if I have any
toast in the house.
- [Servo] The sad
side of beatniks,
beyond the bongos
and the goatees,
lays pain.
- Edward Platt will be
back in "Shaft In Africa."
(whirring)
Say Joel,
why hasn't that conductor
guy, Merit Stone,
been in more movies?
He's pretty good.
- Yeah.
- (French accent) Ah ha,
so I see you too have
fallen into the trap.
- Right, why are you
dressed like Raleigh Fingers
at a Playboy party?
- Aw, what do you mean by that?
- Crow I'm not sure
but I think he's
playing the role
of Hercule Poirot,
the great detective.
- (French accent)
That is right Joel,
I suppose you are
all wondering--
- Wondering why I have
gathered you here today.
- Don't you ever step on
my line again, please.
I am here to solve the
great Merit Stone mystery.
- Uh, that's great, Tom,
but we've got a letter
here to read.
It comes from a Pat--
- Oh come on guys, please?
- Okay, Tom, what is the
great Merit Stone mystery?
- Thank you, Joel, now if
you will grab the visual aid
I have prepared and follow
along with me, please?
- Okay, got it.
- No one is to leave the room.
Now then, we all agree
that the Gary Busey like
conductor from "The Rebel
Set" is Merit Stone, right?
- Right.
- Wrong!
How could you be so
stupid, you make me puke!
- Geez, calm down, it's
just Merit Stone, Tom.
- And what is it that led you
pig dogs to the conclusion
that it was Merit Stone?
Gypsy!?
- 'Cause he was in "Earth vs.
Spider" and "The Tormented?"
- Wrong!
I too almost fell for
that foolish trap.
Joel, Merit Stone's name
appears in the credits to
"Earth vs. The Spider," "The
Magic Sword," and "Tormented."
Put them on the board please.
- Okay, got it.
- Thank you.
But, the Gary Busey conductor
guy physically appears
in "Earth Vs. Spider,"
"Rebel Set," "Giant Leeches,"
and "The Tormented."
Something was wrong.
They didn't match.
I put my gray matter together
and I realized that
Jack Kosslyn appears in
"The Magic Sword," and
"The Earth Vs. The Spider."
- You have a lot of
free time, don't you?
- Quiet fool!
Was it possible that
Jack Kosslyn was
actually Merit Stone?
And vice versa?
- Yes?
- No!
- Uh, no?
- Yes!
His name did not appear
in "The Rebel Set,"
"The Giant Leeches,"
or "Tormented."
I was back at the beginning.
Then a major break in the case.
Gene Roth's name appears
in the credits of
"Earth Vs. Spider," "Rebel
Set," "Giant Leeches,"
and "The Tormented."
(laughs)
I had my man.
Gentlemen, I put it
to you that Gene Roth
is actually Merit Stone.
- I'm so relieved.
- I plan to celebrate
with a bottle of
Chateau Marmont '52, and
perhaps a bit of brie.
- Whoa, whoa,
whoa, wait up here,
if Gene Roth is Merit Stone,
and Merit Stone is in "The
Magic Sword," with Jack Kosslyn,
couldn't Jack Kosslyn
actually be Merit Stone?
And transitively, Jack
Kosslyn could be Gene Roth.
- No, no, no, no, you silly man,
'cause we have a visual
idea of Merit, I mean--
- But you don't have a
visual idea of Jack Kosslyn.
- Not as such, but.
- Well then Jack Kosslyn
could be Merit Stone.
- And if Jack Kosslyn is
Merit Stone, and Merit Stone
is in "Tormented"
with Gene Roth,
then who is Jack Kosslyn
and couldn't Jack Kosslyn
be Gene Roth?
(stuttering)
(surge)
- Oh.
We gotta stop doing
that to that poor kid.
What do you think, sirs?
- Gene Roth.
Gene Roth was in "She Demons."
The 1958 film with
Irish McCallahan.
But Jack Kosslyn,
Jack Kosslyn wasn't
in "She Demons!"
(crying)
So who is Merit Stone?
Dear God, who is Merit Stone?
- I'll get you for this, Joel.
- [Frank] Who is Merit Stone!?
(reverent music)
- I am bugged.